cpaaustralia.com.au 2004-06-06

# Privacy statement

##   
Background

From 21 December 2001, the Privacy Amendment (private Sector) Act 2000 ("The Act") applies to private sector organisations, including CPA Australia (ABN 64 008 392 452) ('CPA'). The Act requires private sector organisations like us to comply with 10 National Privacy Principles (NPPs). The NPPs establish minimum standards in relation to the collection, holding, use disclosure, management, access, correction and disposal of Personal Information about natural persons. For a summary of the NPPs, click here.

##   
Scope

This Privacy Statement applies to this website which is operated by CPA Australia under the domain name www.cpaonline.com.au ('the CPA website'). However this Privacy Statement is subject to any specific provisions about privacy that may be contained in other sections of the CPA website. In the event of any inconsistency between the provisions of this Privacy Statement and such other specific provisions, the latter shall prevail.

##   
Commitment

CPA is committed to protecting the privacy and security of Personal Information collected about you. This Privacy Statement explains how the Personal Information collected about you online will be handled by us.

From time to time we may amend information provided on this website, including this Privacy Statement. Consequently you are encouraged to visit the CPA website and this Privacy Statement on a regular basis.

**By visiting the CPA website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Statement.**

##   
Personal Information

'Personal Information' means information or an opinion about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained from the information. 

##   
Collection of personal information

The type of Personal Information that CPA collects about you online, depends on how you use the CPA website. For example, we will collect Personal Information about you if you register with CPA as a member; register with CPA Online to use the PD Online service or enrol into an event online; enrol in CPA Program and/or Public Practice Program, order a product; post messages to forums; publish resumes; publish jobs or set up a job alert in Recruitment and Careers; participate in a discussion group; communicate to us via e-mail; or volunteer survey information.

Generally speaking, the purpose of collection and the minimum information which you must provide us, will be conveyed to you at the time of collection.  

##   
Collection of information that is not personal information

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that a website transfers to your browser for identification purposes. CPA may send cookies to your computer while you are accessing the CPA website.

Cookies are used on the CPA website:  

  * to reduce the need for members to re-enter their member ID and password during visits to the CPA website;  

  * for internal review; and
  * to track progress through PD Online e-learning modules.

CPA reserves the right to collect Personal Information through the use of cookies in the future. If we do so, we will amend this Privacy Statement to advise users that CPA is collecting Personal Information in this way, and the purposes for which that Personal Information will be used.

In the future, CPA may give third parties the ability to assign cookies to users of the CPA website, for example, as part of an arrangement for the CPA website to carry advertisements for other websites. If this occurs, we will amend this Privacy Statement to advise users of the type of information that such cookies collect, as well as the use to which such information will be put.

### Browser details

A user's Browser details are collected by CPA for statistical purposes.

##   
Use and disclosure of Personal Information

### How we use and disclose Personal Information collected about you on this site.

CPA may use and disclose Personal Information collected about you on this site:

  * for the purposes outlined at the time of collection;  

  * for purposes directly related to those purposes outlined at the time of collection;  

  * for direct marketing purposes;  

  * to keep you informed of Professional Development activities;  

  * when CPA is required or authorised by or under law to disclose the information;  

  * when reasonably necessary to protect or enforce CPA's legal rights or interests or to defend any claims made against CPA by any person;  

  * when otherwise permitted by the Act.

If you wish to opt out of any direct marketing, please inform your local CPA office or select the 'opt out box' on your Membership Renewal Form. 

If you wish to opt out of receiving information on Professional Development and associated activities administered by CPA Australia, please contact your local CPA Professional Development office. 

Otherwise we will treat the Personal Information collected about you through this website in confidence. We will not sell, trade, rent or give away that Personal Information without your consent.  

### Ad servers 

We do not partner with or have special relationships with ad server companies.

##   
Data Security

### Security

We use industry standard encryption technologies (such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology) when transferring and receiving data through CPA Online. SSL is compatible with Netscape, Internet Explorer, AOL, Web TV and most other browsers. If your browser is not equipped with SSL, or if you are at all concerned about sending information such as credit card details over the Internet, we encourage you to contact your local CPA office to make alternative arrangements.

We take reasonable steps to protect Personal Information from misuse and loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Our personnel are trained to treat Personal Information with the utmost confidentiality. You can help by ensuring that you log out of the CPA Online website when you have finished using it. If you become aware of any security breach, please let us know as soon as possible.

Although CPA takes reasonable steps to protect Personal Information, we cannot guarantee that the CPA Online website is 'hacker-proof'.

When Personal Information is no longer required, reasonable steps are taken to destroy or permanently de-identify the information.   

##   
Access and correction

### Access

If you would like to access or correct Personal Information collected about you through the CPA Online website, please contact your local CPA office. CPA will generally allow you to access such information (although a fee may be imposed). Members may access the following types of Personal Information directly through CPA Online:

  * unique identifier information (membership number and password);  

  * transaction information (purchase dates, amounts and types of purchases);  

  * contact information (name, address, e-mail address and telephone number). 

### Correction

If you believe that any Personal Information collected about you through this website is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date, you may request correction of that information by contacting your local CPA office.  

##   
Contact details and complaints 

If you feel that this Privacy Statement is not being followed, please contact your local CPA office or the [Privacy Officer](mailto:liz.granger@cpaaustralia.com.au). 

CPA Online's Privacy policy
